

## Profile

I am an Artificial Intelligence Engineer with 5 years of experience in software development, teaching coding, and automation. My expertise lies in building AI applications, software development, and data engineering.

With prior 10 years of experience, I possess a comprehensive perspective on problem-solving and solution-finding. This is complemented by my effective business communication skills and project management experience, gained from leading and contributing to various projects.

# Employment History

Artificial Intelligence Engineer at techXflow d.o.o. (self-employed)
November 2023

- Al Product Management: Assessing technical feasibility of Al products, leading iterative development, implementing data-centric approaches, managing ambiguity, and fostering continuous learning.
- AI Product Development:

Large Language Models (LLM):ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini, Open-source models

Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), Al agents

- Software Development: Python, SQL, JavaScript (React)
- Data Engineering: ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) pipelines
- Cloud Platforms: GCP and AWS

# Teacher & Head of Regional Compeatence Center at Technical School Čakovec, Čakovec

September 2018 — November 2023

- Led Comprehensive Lectures and Workshops: Covered subjects, including coding (Python, Flutter), automation, and business communication.
- Promoted a Culture of Experimentation: Fostered a learning environment that encouraged trying new things, practical application of theoretical knowledge, and viewing mistakes as essential learning steps.
- Played a prominent role in the implementation of two EU projects valued at €7.5 million

# Head of International Projects and Sales Network at ENERGY PLUS d.o.o., Ludbreg

January 2016 — July 2018

- Supported top-tier international clients and presented the company at fairs
- Worked on LED lighting projects documentation and investment projects, emphasizing Energy Performance Contracting.

#### **Details**

Croatia

00385992656398

mario.klobucaric@gmail.com

#### Links

Personal Page Company Page LinkedIn GitHub

#### **Skills**

Python

JavaScript/React

SQL

LLMs (ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini)

**RAG & Vectorbases** 

**REST APIs** 

Data Science & ML

Flutter

VS Code/ Cursor

Jupyter Notebook

Git/GitHub

GCP / AWS

Firebase

fastAPI

Docker

Langchain/LangGraph

crewAl

LangSmith

### Languages

Croatian

**English** 

German

## Agency Director at Međimurska energetska agencija d.o.o., Čakovec

January 2013 — January 2016

- Directed agency operations, resource management, growth strategies and successfully transformed the agency's financial standing toward complete self-sustainability.
- Managed multiple energy-focused projects and campaigns, promoting, and implementing energy efficiency and renewable energy adoption.

## Licensed Designer at DORS PROJEKT d.o.o., Čakovec

August 2010 — December 2012

- Designed electrical installations for various sectors, including "smart home" and photovoltaic plants.
- · Consulted on renewable energy regulations and privileged producer status.

## Designer at ZG-PROJEKT d.o.o., Zagreb

November 2007 — July 2010

- · Designed electrical installations for highways, tunnels, and road
- Estimated savings for lighting fixture replacements

## Development Engineer at V-elin d.o.o., Čakovec

June 2006 — September 2007

- Assisted in digital/analog system development and contributed to water monitoring projects.
- Prepared technical documentation and supported related software.

## Education

## 56 ECTS, Faculty of Organization and Informatics, Varaždin

2017 - 2018

- Specialization: Teachers Education (Pedagogical/Psychological/Didactic/Methodical)
- GPA: 4.55/5

# University Specialist of Strategic Entrepreneurship, 60 ECTS, Faculty of Economics, Zagreb

2008 - 2011

- Thesis: Leadership in Social Responsibility & Social Entrepreneurship
- GPA: 4.6/5

## Graduate Electrical Engineer (Industrial Electronics), 274 ECTS, Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing, Zagreb

- Thesis: Multichannel Receiver for Surface Electromyography
- GPA: 4.15/5

### **Hobbies**

Reading: Technology & Future, People & Mindset, Personal Growth

Others: Running, Playing Guitar

# Natural Science and Mathematics Gymnasium, Čakovec

1996 — 2000

Awards: 1st (3x) & 3rd (3x) in County Mathematics Competitions (13-18 years)

## Courses

DeepLearning.AI: Data Engineering (AWS) - Professional Specialization, Coursera

October 2024 — December 2024

Various online courses on topics: Python, LLMs, RAG, Vector Databases, Data Science, ML, Flutter, GCP and similar, - Udemy, DeepLearning.AI

2019 — 2024

# **★** Projects

- Al-Powered Web-based Platform for Energy-Efficient Renovations and Renewable Energy Consulting
- Agentic workflows + RAG
- MCP server + Claude Desktop
- Text to SQL agentic app with open-source models
- Educational Assistant App Study Buddy Frontend (Flutter), Backend (Flask)
- Machine learning manual based on Kaggles Titanik dataset
- Robotic arm system with Python GUI on Raspberry PI
- Raspberry PI web server for environmental data visualization
- Webpages